Elien Baguidy

West Palm Beach, FL 33407 superdeveloper0217@gmail.com +1 315 636 4392

Senior Full Stack & Web3 engineer offering over 10 years of experience in web application development, blockchain projects.

Owned an in-depth practical and applicable knowledge of technical subjects from programming languages to modern frameworks for web development.

Worked on Blockchain startups and projects and got hand-on experience in crypto projects.

Possess a demonstrated ability to work on multiple projects independently and as part of a team.

Work Experience

Senior Full Stack Engineer

Posley - Remote January 2023 to October 2023

- Integrated web3.js and ethers.js into React, Next.js web applications for MVP & product version.
- Implemented multiple wallet support using Wagmi.
- UI/UX design with React

Senior Web3 Engineer

Laguna(NUON) - Remote January 2022 to March 2023

- Integrated web3.js and ethers.js into React, Next.js and Vue.js web applications for MVP & product version.
- Implemented multiple wallet support using RainbowKit and Wagmi.
- Developed smart contracts with Smart contracts, hardhat and Opeasea.
- Developed The Graph backend for tracking events & storing statistics data.
- Maintained & updated projects according to the business requirements.

Web3 Engineer

Snowball - Remote May 2021 to December 2021

- · Integrated ethers.js into React project.
- Wrote contracts for stable vault with lead smart contract developer.
- · Maintained project & updated features

Senior Full-stack Engineer

Maryoku - Remote October 2020 to June 2021

- Implemented UI/UX with React, Angular, Vue js
- Developed REST APIs with Python and integrate them into front end applications
- Design data structure and manage MongoDB Database
- Deploy web on AWS Lightsail virtual machine and maintain it

Full-stack Engineer

RockPeaks - Washington, NC October 2017 to April 2020

- Implemented new UI/UX using Angular, React, Next.js, SCSS and Bootstrap.
- Integrated APIs using GraphQL and React Apollo.
- Upgraded and maintained a number for front end projects according to the customers' requirements.
- Developed reusable components with React and Storybook.
- Develop mobile app with Java Native app.
- Performed all levels of testing from Unit test to Acceptance test

Education

Bachelor of Science

University of Florida - Gainesville, FL May 2009 to May 2013

Skills

- Software Testing and Validation
- React
- Vue
- Blockchain Development
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- · Algorithm design and structure
- Code Analysis and Development
- Team Management
- Code and Quality Standards
- Angular
- Mobile app development
- Source and Version Control: Git, Github
- Project Management
- Programming Languages
- Database Management Software
- JavaScript
- Java
- Bootstrap
- Node.js
- MySQL
- REST
- JSON
- MongoDB
- Agile

- Front-End Development
- Unit Testing
- Docker
- ASP.NET
- HTML5
- CSS
- APIs
- Software Development
- AWS
- PHP
- Web Services
- User Interface (UI)
- Web Development
- Next.js
- Blockchain
- Web3
- Android
- React Native
- Spring Boot
- Grails
- Nest

Links

https://github.com/neymarjohn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/elien-baguidy-823aa428a/